《綱手 : サクラ ナルトを頼むぞ》
Sakura… I leave Naruto
in your hands!
《綱手 : あいつはいつだって
里の希望だ》
He has always been
our village's symbol of hope.
Ever since that time,
everyone has always…
《綱手 : みんなにとって
あのときからずっと》
(シズネ)自来也様は 何と？
What did Lord Jiraiya say?
うむ… 修業は 順調らしい。
It seems the training
is going well.
(ナルト)ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身の術！
大玉螺旋丸！
Giant Rasengan!
(自来也)
ここ２年あまりの修業で➡
The force of your Rasengan
has grown in
just two years of training.
螺旋丸の威力は増しておるのう。
そろそろ次の段階に進む日が
来たのかもしれんな。
Perhaps it's about time
we move on to the next level.
次の段階？
ああ。
Next level?
Yes…
どうすんだってばよ。
What're you gonna do?
お前の内なる力を使うときが
来たかもしれんということだ。
Perhaps the time has come
to utilize your inner power.
それって…。
Is that...?
うむ 命がけの修業に
なるやもしれんぞ。
Yes… You may have to put your life
on the line for this training.
ああ 望むところだ。
All right, I'm ready for it!
あれから もう２年か。
It's been two years already…
あのガキが里へ戻ってくる日も
近いかもしれんな。
The day that brat returns
may soon be upon us.
LEAF HOSPITAL
(シズネ)ナルト君は 不思議な存在です。
Naruto is a mysterious being…
この２年間
ずっと里から離れているのに。
He's been away from the village
for two whole years and yet…
Inuzuka Style!
Man Beast Transformation Combo!
(キバ)犬塚流 人獣混合変化
双頭狼！
Two-Headed Wolf!
(キバ)牙狼牙！
Wolf Fang Over Fang!
(シズネ)その存在感は
どんどん大きくなっていて。
…his presence keeps on growing.
(ネジ)大丈夫か？
Are you all right?
(テンテン)もう限界。
I'm at my limit!
(リー)あと10周です。
Just ten more laps!
こんなんで へばっていたら
ナルト君に笑われますよ。
If you stop now,
Naruto will laugh at you!
みんな ナルト君を意識して➡
Everyone seems to keep Naruto
in their thoughts as they train!
修業に励んでいるようなんです。
通信鷹？
A messenger hawk!
どこから？
Where?!
(由良)風影様。
Lord Kazekage!
木ノ葉隠れの里
五代目 火影様より➡
A Shinobi Hawk has
brought a message
忍鷹で書状が届けられました。
from the Hidden Leaf's
Fifth Hokage.
The New Chunin Exams
(シカマル)うん？
ったく 待ちくたびれたぜ。
I was getting tired of waiting.
(テマリ)わざわざお出迎えかい？
ご苦労だな。
You're our welcoming party?
Thank you for coming to meet us.
ふん めんどくせえけど➡
Well, it's a drag,
but seeing as it's Lord Kazekage…
相手が風影様とあってはな。
お待ちしていました。
Welcome.
Here is the data from
the Chunin Exams two years ago.
２年前の 中忍試験の資料です。
A total of 153 entrants.
総勢153名 参加者の里の内訳➡
Information about
the entrant's village,
the three rounds of exams,
and the qualifying statistics
一 二 三次試験 進出率など➡
have been compiled
for easy reading.
わかりやすく表にしてあります。
本選中断の理由や経緯などは➡
But you would know more
about the reason behind
皆様のほうがお詳しいでしょうが。
the interruption of the final round
and its chronology.
Due to the suspension
of the last Chunin Exams,
前回 中忍試験が
中断されたのを受け➡
合同中忍試験を木ノ葉主催で
行いたいと思うんだが。
the Hidden Leaf would like to
sponsor a combined Chunin Exam.
木ノ葉隠れの協力もあり➡
Thanks in part to
the Hidden Leaf's cooperation,
我が里も この２年ほどは
安定を取り戻し➡
the situation in
our village has stabilized
during the last two years…
特に 教育カリキュラムにおいては
すばらしい成果が出た。
In particular,
our training curriculum
has been very successful
and we have developed more genin
中忍試験にたえうる下忍たちも
育っている。
who are qualified to
take the Chunin Exams.
では 中忍試験主催に
異存はないな？
Then you have no objection
to our sponsoring an event?
(カンクロウ)その前に
火影様の本音を聞きたい。
Before that, Lady Hokage…
What's your true motive?
本音とは？
"True motive?"
今のタイミングで
中忍試験を再開する理由だ。
I mean the timing of this thing.
Why hold the Chunin Exams now?
If the reason is lack of personnel…
人材不足が理由なら➡
you could have done this sooner.
もっと早く開くことも
できたはずじゃん。
わかった 腹を割って話そう。
All right.
I'll be honest.
まず 第一の理由は➡
The first reason is to gauge
the reactions of
表面上 平穏を装う 五大国➡
each of the villages
within the Five Great Nations.
それぞれの里の反応を見たい
ということ。
Each, who on the surface,
purport to be at peace.
合同中忍試験への対応次第で➡
Their response to having
the combined Chunin Exams
その本心が透けて見えるはず。
will reveal their true feelings.
第二には 暁の動静を
探る意味もある。
The second reason is to
investigate Akatsuki's movements.
彼らは 各里の尾獣を
狙っているといわれているが➡
It's said that they seek
the Tailed Beasts from each village,
ここ２年 その動きが
つかめなくなっている。
but they've been awfully quiet
these past two years.
中忍試験にかこつけて
里を開放し➡
You want to use the Chunin Exams
to open the village
わざとすきを作り➡
to create an opportunity
to lure the Akatsuki out?
暁を誘いだそうというわけか。
そうだ。 そろそろ
暁のやつらも焦れて➡
Yes. The Akatsuki have
probably grown impatient
and are ready to make a move.
動きが活発になるタイミングだ。
そのような危険な目に…。
(我愛羅)待て。
This is a risky—
Hold on.
こたびの中忍試験
風影就任のお披露目もかねて➡
These Chunin Exams…
The Hidden Sand
would like to host it,
砂隠れの主催としたい。
in conjunction with
my introduction as Kazekage.
(ホムラ)それはならぬ。
(コハル)そうじゃ。
That will not do.
The Hidden Leaf must
sponsor these Chunin Exams.
この中忍試験は
前回の仕切り直し。
木ノ葉主催でなければ
筋が通らぬ。
It's so that we may finish
what we started previously.
うむ そのとおりじゃ。
Yes, absolutely.
このことは
風影様の一存では決められない。
Lord Kazekage cannot
decide this all by himself.
里の上役会議にもはからねば。
He must consult the village elders.
ああ 連絡を取り合う時間が
必要だ。
Yeah. We need time to contact them.
この件に関しては➡
Let's come back to this again
at the next meeting.
次回の会議ということに
してほしい。
フンッ。
うむ よかろう。
Fine.
この議題は 次回の会議で。
We'll settle this during
the next meeting.
何か めんどくせえことに
なったな。
This is becoming a drag.
ああ 突然 我愛羅が
あんなことを言いだすなんて。
Yeah. I didn't expect Gaara
to make such an announcement.
本当に何も聞いてなかったんだな。
He really didn't tell you anything?
寝耳に水さ。
That came out of nowhere.
ま あいつには
あいつの考えがあるんだろうが。
Well, he probably
has his own ideas.
(我愛羅)頼むぞ。
I leave it to you.
もし 火影の言うとおり➡
If the Hokage is right
and the Akatsuki make their move,
暁が現れたら
標的にされるのは お前じゃん。
you're going to be
their target, right?
敵の狙いが尾獣なら
遅かれ早かれ結果は同じ。
If the enemy wants
the Tailed Beasts,
they'll come for me
sooner or later.
なら俺自身が
オトリになって迎えうつ。
Then I'll just be the bait
and take them down.
何言ってんだ！
What are you saying?!
新しい風影として お前を迎え➡
The village has welcomed you
as their new Kazekage
里は いまだ
安定していないんだぞ。
but things are still unstable!
わかっている。
あっ。
I'm aware of that.
俺の風影就任を
よく思っていない者➡
I know that some are not happy
that I have become the Kazekage…
機会さえあれば→
and would welcome
an opportunity to kill me.
亡き者にしようと思う
勢力が存在することは…。
じゃあ なおさら
里での開催なんて。
Then why would you even consider
hosting the event in our village?!
だからこそ
砂隠れで中忍試験を開きたい。
It is precisely why I want
the Chunin Exams
in Hidden Sand Village.
まさか お前が
おびき出したいのは➡
You can't be serious!
It's not the Akatsuki
you want to lure out…
暁じゃなく 里の反逆者どもか？
But the rebels in the village?
そりゃ危険すぎるじゃん。
That's just too dangerous.
(由良)
今度の合同中忍試験に関して➡
Regarding the combined
Chunin Exams under discussion…
風影様は 砂隠れの里での開催を
希望しておられる。
It is Lord Kazekage's desire
to host the event
in Hidden Sand Village.
他国に対して➡
He intends to introduce himself
to the other nations.
風影就任のお披露目のおつもりか。
それはどうかな。
Is that wise?
ここ しばらく
なりを潜めているが➡
While things have been quiet
for a while now,
我愛羅が
恐るべき兵器であることには➡
it does not change
the fact that Gaara is
"a military weapon to be feared."
いまだ変わりはない。
我愛羅が生きているかぎり➡
As long as Gaara lives,
この里に
真の平穏が訪れることはない。
this village can never
be truly at peace.
風影様は
こたびの二次試験の会場に➡
For the second round of the exam,
Lord Gaara intends to
砂隠れの魔の砂漠がふさわしいと
提案するおつもりらしい。
suggest the Demon Desert
as a suitable arena.
我ら砂隠れは 全面的に
これをバックアップするものとする。
And we, the Hidden Sand,
will do our utmost to support him!
チッ！ 我らのこと
由良に気づかれたか。
Yura is on to us.
いや 我愛羅に対する不安は
皆が持っている。
No…everyone is
uneasy about Gaara.
ああ あれだけでは
クーデターの計画までは悟られ…。
But that's not enough
to plan a coup d'état.
これはこれは先輩方。
Well, well…my elders…
こんなところに
いらっしゃいましたか。
Of all places to find you.
何の用だ？ 我らは→
What do you want?
We said we are in favor
of Lord Gaara's plan.
風影様のご提案に
賛成だと言ったはずだが。
いえ
言うのを忘れておりましたが➡
Nothing, I just forgot to tell you…
風影様は ご自身で監督官として
現場に立つおつもりらしい。
Lord Gaara plans to
personally supervise the exam site.
我らも 気を引き締めて
準備せねば➡
We'll have to be very careful
with preparations.
なんといっても
二次試験のサバイバルゲームは➡
After all, the second round
is a survival test
毎回 死者が出ている。
and there are always fatalities.
万が一にも 監督官たる
風影様の身の上に➡
Why who's to say
nothing will happen
to the supervisor himself,
Lord Gaara…
何かが起こらないとも限らない。
では 失礼します。
Excuse me…
あくまで 事故として
風影を亡き者にするには➡
So this is the perfect opportunity
to get rid of the Kazekage
絶好の機会というわけか。
and make it look purely accidental…
しかし 人柱力だぞ。
手はある。
But he is a Jinchuriki.
There's a way.
初代の人柱力 分福殿が
一時的に守鶴を閉じ込めるのに➡
The first Jinchuriki, Bunpuku,
was able to temporarily seal
Shukaku into a teapot.
使った茶釜は使える。
We can use that…
(シズネ)いかがなさいます？ 綱手様。
What is your decision,
Lady Tsunade?
うむ…。
(綱手)２年前 自来也は
次に暁がナルトを狙うのは➡
Two years ago, Jiraiya had intel
that said the Akatsuki would
３～４年後だろうという
情報をつかんでいた。
target Naruto
in three or four years.
あれから２年が経ち
そろそろ暁のやつらも➡
And two years have passed…
I'm sure they're itching
to make a move.
動きが活発になる頃だ。
まさか ナルト君をオトリにして!?
You're not going to use Naruto
as bait are you?
いや 木ノ葉隠れの里の火影として
そんなことはできない。
No…
As the Hokage of
Hidden Leaf Village,
I cannot do such a thing.
では その役目を影風様に？
Don't tell me…Lord Kazekage
will assume that role?
好都合にも 向こうから
言い出してくれた。
As luck would have it,
he was the one who proposed it.
(シズネ)しかし ご意見番たちが
認めるでしょうか？
But will the advisors agree?
そちらは 共同開催ということで
納得してもらう。
I'll placate them
by suggesting a joint-sponsorship.
これ以上の譲歩はできぬ。
We can't negotiate any further.
先日の 風影よりの提案を
検討したのだが…。
I looked over the plans
you submitted…
どうだろう 木ノ葉隠れと
砂隠れの共同開催としては。
What do you think about
a joint-sponsorship
with the Hidden Leaf?
筆記試験の第一次は
木ノ葉隠れの里で。
We'll hold round one,
the written exam,
at the Hidden Leaf…
二次サバイバルテストの場所は➡
And the Hidden Sand
will host the site of
the second round survival test.
砂隠れに
提供してもらうというのでは。
死の森は 試験場として
あまりに知られてしまった。
The Forest of Death has
become too familiar as a test site.
新たな場所が必要だと
思っていたところじゃ。
I was just thinking a new site
would be necessary.
うむ そういうことなら。
Hmm… I agree.
我々には 何の異存もない。
We have no objections.
じゃあな。
中忍試験のとき また会おう。
All right then…
We'll meet again
at the Chunin Exams.
ああ。
何か困ったことが起きたら➡
Yeah…
Come to us if any trouble arises.
相談しな。
なんとかしてやる 泣き虫君。
We'll take care of it, Mr. Crybaby.
ったく 相変わらずだな。
Damn it. She doesn't change.
(カカシ)今回 音隠れからの参加は
ないでしょうから。
The Hidden Sound probably
won't take part this time around…
それ以外の前回参加した里に
招待状を送ればいいんですね？
So should we just send invitations
to everyone else
from the last time?
うむ それに加え
風影のお披露目という名目で➡
Yes. In addition,
send invitations for
the introduction of
the new Kazekage
五大国すべての里に
招待状を出すんだ。
to every village within
the Five Great Nations.
なるほど それで各里の反応を…。
I see…
Then we can monitor
each village's response.
ああ 今 合同中忍試験を再開する
暁以外の もうひとつの目的だ。
Aside from Akatsuki,
this is the other reason
for reopening
the combined Chunin Exams.
はい かしこまりました。
Yes, I understand.
各里に この書状を届けよ。
Deliver this to every village.
中忍試験への招待状である。
はっ！
It's the invitation to
the Chunin Exams.
– Right!
賽は投げられた。
We've put out the bait…
あとは どんな反応が
返ってくるかだ。
Now, let's see how they react.
(シズネ)綱手様 早速➡
Lady Tsunade.
The Hidden Sand replied right away…
砂隠れの里から書状が届きました。
ほう。
Oh…
９組 27名の下忍を
送り込んでくるらしい。
They'll be sending nine teams…
27 genin.
Last time,
they sent 30 in ten teams…
(シズネ)前回は 10組 30名でしたが。
１組 少ないとはいえ➡
Although that's one team short,
今の砂隠れの状況で→
considering the Hidden Sand's
current situation,
one has to commend them
for nurturing this many genin.
よくぞ これだけの下忍を
育て上げたと言うべきだろうな。
(シズネ)はい。
Yes…
それより 他の里からの報告は
まだ届かないのか？
Any word from the other villages?
(シズネ)ああ はい いまだ。
No, not yet.
各里の影は どう反応するかだ。
How will the other Kage respond?
(エー)中忍試験だと!?
Chunin Exams, you say?!
(エー)綱手姫め 調子にのりおって！
Damn that Princess Tsunade!
She's getting carried away!
砂隠れの風影を
まるめこんだうえに➡
She probably coaxed
the Kazekage into cooperating…
一気に五大国の
イニシアチブをとるつもりだな。
…and plans to get the jump on us
within the Five Great Nations.
(シー)どういたします？
(エー)え～い 無視だ。
What will you do?
Ignore her!
無視しておればいい。
Just ignore her!
それと今回の件 誰にも話すな。
Do not mention of word of this,
or the past, to anyone!
特に ビーには悟られるなよ。
Especially Bee!
Do not let him find out!
あいつ こういう
お祭りごとになると➡
Whenever there
are events like this,
ライブだのコンサートだのと言って➡
he gets excited about live concerts
and what not.
はしゃぎ始めるからな。
(ダルイ)実は もう
しゃべっちゃいました。
何？
Actually, I already told him.
What?!
しつこく聞かれたもんで。
He kept asking questions…
I'm sorry.
すみません。
ビー！ ビーはいるか!?
Bee!
Where is Bee?!
まさか あいつ。
Don't tell me…
すぐ ビーを探し出して
ここに連れてこい！
Find Bee immediately
and bring him here!
かしこまりました。
だるいな。
Understood.
This is so dull…
A concert at Hidden Leaf Village…
♪♪(キラービー)「木ノ葉の里で コンサート」
♪♪「中忍試験で チューニング」
Tuning up at the Chunin Exams…
♪♪「キンちゃん先生に
レッスンを受けるっすん」
Take a lesson from Kin-chan Sensei!
いえ～い。
Yay!
ビー 雷影様がお呼びだ 早く戻れ。
Bee! Lord Raikage wants to see you!
Please return!
バカヤロウ コノヤロウ！
Fool, ya fool!
雷影様からは なんと？
What did Lord Raikage say?
残念ながら里内の所用が忙しく➡
Unfortunately, they are swamped
with village business
今回は準備が間に合わないそうだ。
and don't have enough
time to prepare.
(メイ)火影と風影が
何の用向きで書状などを。
Now why would the Hokage
and Kazekage send a letter?
ち… 中忍試験を➡
Seems they're resuming
the Chunin Exams…
再開するらしいのう。
What shall we do?
どうするかのう。
We must consider the matter
with Lord Yagura the Fourth…
(青)四代目 やぐら様の件もあり➡
今は里の立て直しに
集中するのが先決かと。
I believe we should concentrate
on rebuilding the village…
それもそうかのう。
You may have a point.
そうですとも
風影披露の合同開催に➡
Yes!
We can't be wasting
our time participating
参加する余裕はありません。
in a ceremony announcing
the new Kazekage…
《披露？
CEREMONY
Ceremony…
披露宴を開催する
余裕などない》
CAN'T WASTE TIME FOR
A CEREMONY FOR ME
Can't waste time for
a ceremony for me?
黙れ 殺すぞ。
Shut up or I'll kill you.
(青)えっ!?
What?!
やはり こたびの
中忍試験への参加は➡
Perhaps we should forego
the Chunin Exams this time.
見送ろうかのう。
そういたしましょう。
Let's do that.
霧隠れの里も
それどころではないそうだ。
It seem
(オオノキ)こたび
木ノ葉隠れの里より➡
合同中忍試験の
招待状なるものが届いた。
その魂胆は見え見えじゃ。
どうせ 他里の戦力を分析し➡
次の戦いに備えようという➡
算段に違いないんじゃ！
(赤ツチ)そんなもん
叩き返してやるだに。
むろん そのつもりじゃ。
(みんな)おお。
招待状など こうしてやる。
あっ。
(オオノキ)ぬお～！
(綱手)お前は ここに行ってくれ。
雨隠れの里ですね。
ああ いちばん
やっかいなところだ。
出入りする者の
入国審査はもちろん。
滞在期間中の監視も厳重で➡
親族すら簡単には
近づけないといわれる➡
山椒魚の半蔵が治める里だ。
ええ 聞いています。
たとえ合同中忍試験の
書状を持っていても➡
簡単には入れてくれないでしょう。
内政が安定せず➡
クーデターの噂もあるが➡
あまりの閉鎖性に
実態は 一切 知られていない。
ついでに里内の状況でも
探ってみますか？
ああ しかし無理はするな。
皆様 お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！ にっぽんの歌』➡
２時間スペシャル。
オープニングは 五木ひろしさん➡